<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Mousehole</title>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/"/>
<id>https://Dirout.github.io/blog</id>
<entry>
<author>
<name>Mousehole</name>
<email>limesayahi@gmail.com</email>
</author>
<title>A Crack in the Wall</title>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2021/03/13/A Crack in the Wall.html"/>
<pubdate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 15:30:00 +0500</pubdate>
<updated>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 15:30:00 +0500</updated>
<id>https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2021/03/13/A Crack in the Wall.html</id>
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the surface, Bradley and Kathleen were the ideal American couple.
Kathleen, a waifish yet perfectly kempt woman of 32, kept a
household that was the envy of all the other home-bound wives on
the street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bradley, a successful lawyer in their moderately-sized, up-and-coming
city, was a very proud man, both of his sparkling new home in
the suburbs, and of his much sought-after position at his firm.
Indeed, they were a jewel in the crown of the American upper-middle
class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Kathleen had a secret: a mouse breeding business down in the
basement—and not &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; in the sense of breeding mice. It was not
like the love that was expected of a woman of her status, approaching
middle age. No, this love was something more passionate, scandalous,
and fiery than what this old maid was expected to get from Bradley—
for how could a man compare to a well-bred mouse?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, Bradley and Kathleen had been like most other young couples
in their generation: brought together by a baseline level of regard,
convenient circumstances, and, on the part of Bradley, at least, an
average amount of attraction. Alas, as time went on, the unremarkable
circumstances upon which their relationship was founded began to
deteriorate—or, rather, crumble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When, for the millionth time, Bradley came home with ‘exciting news’
regarding his job status, a ‘blow to those rat-race millions’, Kathleen
realized that her life brought her no joy, as it brought her no purpose
or progress. She needed an investment, a passion, and true companionship.
What then, she thought, could be better than a mouse? Short, sweet,
adorable and furry, their squeaks could make Bradley’s sweaty, intrusive
hands bearable most nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, one sunny morning, after Bradley had just stomped his way over
her freshly vacuumed carpet and out of the house with hardly a, “See
ya later, sweet-cheeks,” to the woman who did most everything for
him, Kathleen had an idea: she would finally get those mice she’d been
yearning for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She ran out the door with a smile on her face and went down to ‘Clompin’
Clive’s Curious Creatures’ and picked out some bright white mice, with
red in their eyes. She named the girls ‘Lucy’, ‘Liza’, and ‘Lexapro’,
and the boys ‘Matthew’, ‘Ishmael’, and ‘Ernesto’. Ernesto was clearly
the alpha,&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
<author>
<name>Evan Gabriel Burke</name>
<email>evanburke619@gmail.com</email>
</author>
<title>A Perpetual Morning</title>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2019/07/01/A Perpetual Morning.html"/>
<pubdate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 21:19:00 +0500</pubdate>
<updated>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 21:19:00 +0500</updated>
<id>https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2019/07/01/A Perpetual Morning.html</id>
<content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The bleakest skies are not those of winter&lt;/em&gt;. That sentence, a mere phrase,  was the result of three years. Each day, all three years, spent on eight unchanged words. Hell, I wasn’t even sure I knew what I meant by it. The sentence just seemed to come to me one day and I had never felt more compelled to write something.  Meg had always said that writing was a pointless venture. Apparently, she was right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;I paused for a moment and let the cursor blink. Then, as I had done so many times before, got up from my desk and headed out through the living room to the back door. &lt;em&gt;The bleakest skies are not those of winter.&lt;/em&gt; A damned blatant lie. Looking outside, I could see that the sky was in fact undeniably bleak today (the bleakest I had ever seen it), along with the rest of the winter-worn, half-derelict, Midwestern landscape. I saw as well that the ice of early February had killed the snowdrops that were starting to come up in the lot next door and stared at them for a minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;All three years. What did it matter anyway? The novel wasn’t ever going to be written in the first place. I’d never meant to write it and yet I was still waiting and trying to write. Undoubtedly, I never would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;A gust of wind caught my attention. It was 10 A.M., making today the eighth day of my sabbatical, or, alternatively, the eighth day that I had risen, lacking  any ambition, and crept to the back patio to smoke after Meg had left and I had canned at least seven drafts. She never liked it when I smoked because by her observation it made me irritable and tired. This was something that I could not dispute. It became a daily ritual for me, nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;From my back pocket, I pulled out a half-empty pack that I had been working on over the past two days. The abraded texture of the box relieved my shaking. I took out my Clipper and lit one of the cigarettes, then stayed outside and smoked the rest of the pack. I went back inside again at noon but didn’t try to write again until later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Sometime after four o’clock, Amos, our neighbor in the apartment above, stopped by for coffee and a cigarette or two as he did most days. Amos, whose appearance rendered a deep weariness, was short but exceptionally wiry for his age. His salient features, though, were his pale, slate-colored eyes that reminded me of an overcast daybreak in November. It was the eyes that always spoke to me. He was 57 years old, employed as a part-time janitor, and a veteran of no more than six failed marriages and engagements. In all, he was a fine man to talk with. He never said much about himself, but instead listened and gave whatever forthright advice he could offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;We sat on the back porch in the lawn chairs and watched the evening snow and listened to the accompanying sound of cars on the highway nearby. It was cold, but not unbearable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;After pouring him a cup of coffee and lighting another cigarette, I said what I had always said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“It’s the first sentence. The first damned sentence, Amos. I don’t know what else to say. I’ve been sitting here for the past three years writing reviews and trying to make a good story when I can. I know what I want to write down, what I want to have, but I can’t figure out just how to say it. I’ve tried, and I really have tried, you know? I don’t know what happened and I’m tired of writing bullshit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Amos sipped his coffee and looked out toward the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I don’t know what to tell you this time. I’ve never tried writing anything real before in my life and I guess I don’t know what I would do if I were you either. Sometimes you just have to wait until something good comes to you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Well, shit. Guess that solves my problems then.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;We both chuckled and didn’t say anything else for a while thereafter. This wasn’t uncommon when we talked. It was a tacit principle of our association that some things were better left unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;We continued to listen to the highway, finished a pot of coffee and most of another pack, and went inside. The snow had picked up and all but the incandescent porch light was invisible then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Meg came home at 8:04 and promptly asked that Amos leave for the night. Amos left, thus leaving Meg and I standing alone together, face to face, in our front room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Meg looked at me, walked to the counter, and with an almost inaudible sigh, placed down her coat and bag. I was not a stranger to these dangerously tired sighs of hers. She looked up at me and was silent for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Simon, really? You know I can’t stand Amos spending all of his time at our apartment and you know I can’t stand it when you sit around here smoking all day, especially during the week,” Her tone turned colder and angrier, as did the condition of the weather outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;”Can I come home for one goddamned day and not be disappointed? One goddamned day? Is this what it’s going to be like? What’s happened to you? I can’t understand why on Earth you’d rather sit around and smoke all day, killing yourself, wallowing in self-pity about your writing with a 60-year-old janitor, for Christ’s sake, instead of doing your damned job. What have I told you? Why can’t you get it through your head, Simon? You’re not trying, and I’m trying, but goddamnit, Simon, you’re not! You’ve been a terrible boyfriend recently and you’re never going to get published because you never-”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;At this point I had stopped listening as Meg continued to yell until she struck me across the face, bringing my attention back to her. My lower lip stung momentarily and began bleeding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;I couldn’t blame her, really. I never could. She had a rough job and a burdened mind and an ineffective way of coping with them. Excessive drinking, inevitably, numbed both her pain and her capacity for self-restraint. I couldn’t ever blame her, though, even through the screaming and the hitting and hot, maudlin tears that were being directed at me. I thought I loved her in a way that I could never seem to understand except that it hurt and I never asked why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Then, swiftly, as imperceptibly as one falls asleep after remembering a dream and for reasons that I could not yet comprehend, I remembered the day my father died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;I hardly remember the death of my father, though pieces of it seem to come back every so often. They come dimly and at times when I find myself least likely to have thought of them at all. Perhaps such an event might stand out among a person’s memories, but by some manner of unconscious suppression or alteration I struggle to recollect more than broken-up scenes and nearly-familiar feelings. Regardless, as a droplet of blood ran from my lip and down my chin (Meg maintained long, well-manicured nails, you see), I thought of him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;He had died of alcohol poisoning after drinking two bottles of whiskey in quick succession. I was not aware of this until the hours after, however, when I came home from school in the evening and found him at the kitchen table. My mother, arriving home shortly after me, called an ambulance and followed it to the hospital without so much as a word to me. I never saw him again, excepting the brief funeral she convened at the local chapel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Indisputably, things change when someone dies. I mean this particularly in the sense that after a while, the expectation of life as you knew it goes away and you accept the fact that a death has happened and that you will never be able to do anything about it but move on. Of course, this is precisely what happened to me in the circumstance of my father’s death. He was a good man, but rather absent at times, and I loved him despite this, and despite having known that he would die by his drunkenness eventually. Yet literal deaths are not the only circumstances in which such a change in expectation occurs. I suppose, alike to the way that I both anticipated and accepted my father’s death, that was, in most respects, how I felt about Meg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;See, I loved her because I needed her in a way. I needed her a lot. I do not leave myself blameless when I state that her worrying, along with the stress of her daily life, were factors that led her to be whom she was in the evenings. Nevertheless, and from the beginning, I felt that she would reach her breaking point, or two successive bottles, so to speak, before we would reach a mutual and seamless decline in our love for one another. Even then, I don’t know what I would have done without her, regardless of her strong apprehension toward my writing, for the past three years.
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;My flashback ended and I sat down, still somewhat dazed, in the chair as Meg said nothing, turned, and went into the bedroom. Our apartment was silent except for the sound of the heater and a muffled television from the room next door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Fifteen minutes passed before I entered the bedroom after her. I saw that she had fallen asleep without bothering to get under the comforter or take off her shoes and went back out to get her a blanket. Then, without much thought, I pulled out my rucksack from under the bed and packed for an indefinite amount of time away. I just needed some time. Any at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The apartment was noiseless now and Meg was deeply asleep. As quietly as I could, I retrieved my laptop, wrote a quick note on a pad of paper, exited and locked the apartment, then headed up the stairwell to find Amos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Amos did not lock his door most nights. Any individuals who took to burglarizing him would first find themselves sorely disappointed by the sparse belongings inside and thereupon shot. Tonight, though, I thought to enter his apartment before knocking. I gathered that he would be expecting me at some point after Meg came home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Amos’s apartment retained the strong, intermingled scents of tobacco and birch, as chain-smoking and wood carving were his primary occupations. This was difficult not to be reminded of whenever I opened his door, or when anyone did, for that matter. I stepped inside and turned to the living room to see Amos sitting on his couch and carving the figure of a bird. A barn swallow in flight, it seemed. His ability as a craftsman was truly impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“How’d it go?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“About as well as it usually does.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Not too bad this time?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Well, I am here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Yep. You need a place to sleep, right? The couch is all yours, if you want it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Much obliged.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Give me a second and I’ll take care of the wood shavings.”
Amos swept his work off of the couch and produced a large wool blanket from a chest nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“This should work for you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“It’s just fine for tonight. Thanks again for letting me stay.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Don’t worry about it; you’re good company anyway. Want some coffee? I just put a pot on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I’ll take a cup, if you don’t mind.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“You bet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Amos’ apartment had one bedroom, one bathroom, a modest kitchenette, and a room just wide enough to be considered a living area. As a result, it was easy to find oneself feeling all too close to one’s fellow inhabitant while inside. I didn&#39;t have the option of sleeping somewhere else, small though the place was. About a minute later, Amos reentered the room carrying two cups of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“It looks like the weather’s as good as it’ll get tonight. How about the balcony?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Amos handed me a cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Why not?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;We put on our coats and took the pot of coffee out onto the balcony. The air was motionless and the world seemed immersed in a restless sleep: a few cars moved by on the highway and lights from the city would flicker every so often. I looked out over the railing, past the city, and to the horizon. Funny how fast Prussian blue becomes black in the winter. It’s cold and things just seem to slip by too subtly to notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“You want to talk about it?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Not really. Not this time. I’d say it’s about done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Was it that bad?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Not the worst, actually. I’m just tired of it, that’s all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Have any idea what you’re doing next?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Shit, I don’t have any idea what I’m doing now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“It’s your apartment, isn’t it? If you’re done putting up with the fits, just tell her she’s got a couple days to get her stuff and go. You can’t keep it up: either that woman’s going to kill you with her yelling, or you’re gonna kill yourself by dealing with it forever. It’s up to you, but I’d get the hell out of there. You knew it was gonna happen sometime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“She’s dealing with a lot, Amos.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“So are you, pal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“So what?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“So what? You get the hell out of there, that’s what. You’re wasting your time and you know it. Simon, there’s a point when you need to stop putting up with something and wasting your life, and that’s right now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;There wasn’t anything left to say. Goodbye, maybe. I’ll see you soon. We’ll talk about it at some point. No, I don’t think that we’re going to be able to fix things. Amos was right. I was right for once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Know what?” I said, avoiding eye contact, “I am about done, in fact, I’m about four months past done, but I’m going to need some time to think things over. I can’t kick her out; she doesn’t have anywhere to go. I’ve got to spend some time away somewhere. I don’t know where yet, but it can’t be here. She has the note already.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“About time. You don’t have an idea or anything yet?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“A motel, probably. It doesn’t matter much.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Meg won’t try to call you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Not after reading the note. No, I don’t think so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“You can be sure I’m not telling her anything.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I know.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The next morning was brighter. Sunlight shone blindingly on the snow and the sky was a blazing color; a shade of blue almost too vibrant to look at. It was still cold, but not so harsh as the night before. Everything was stiller now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Turning from the window, I put the last of my belongings into the rucksack and zipped it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“When are you heading out?” Amos said as he entered from the kitchenette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I need to pick up a few things from the store down the street, then I’ll be about ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Sure you don’t need a ride?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“The car’s got a full tank. I’ll be fine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Amos nodded, then glanced at me before going back into the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I’ll call you when I get there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Yep. If you need anything, call anytime. You know I don’t have a whole lot going on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I will,” I said turning back toward the window, “I think I’m going to be alright.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Hang in there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Thanks, Amos. Couldn’t have done it without you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;At this, he grinned. A grin was reassuring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Anytime, Simon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;With a parting wave, I left Amos’ apartment and headed down the steps to my car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Driving away from the city is a dream-like, distant experience. I watched through my mirror as the layers of gray office buildings and apartments faded away into sloping, ashen hills in the distance. Soon they became nothing but trees and a long road ahead of me. Then, nothing but blank sky, a trailing ribbon with evergreens dotted evermore thickly along its sides. As though all of what I knew had become nothing in a matter of minutes, or hours, perhaps. It was difficult to tell. The sun shone even more brightly in the light of the late morning, scattering rivers of light from the bare branches that hung above the road. The land sloped, the forest around was dense, but there was light ahead and it touched everything. At once, the morning was everywhere and always, glowing on the snow, on the trees, and in the sky. Everything was cold and bright and new. Grinning, I opened my window and felt a burst of air wash over me. A grin was always reassuring.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
<author>
<name>Evan Gabriel Burke</name>
<email>evanburke619@gmail.com</email>
</author>
<title>Banks of the Ohio</title>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2019/07/01/Banks of the Ohio.html"/>
<pubdate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 21:19:00 +0500</pubdate>
<updated>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 21:19:00 +0500</updated>
<id>https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2019/07/01/Banks of the Ohio.html</id>
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;﻿&lt;em&gt;Banks of the Ohio&lt;br /&gt;
I asked my love to take a walk,&lt;br /&gt;
Just to walk a little ways,&lt;br /&gt;
Down beside where the waters flow,&lt;br /&gt;
On the banks of the Ohio.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The song played quietly from a phonograph in the back of the diner. An old man listened as he looked to the road that wound over the mountains. There was the old man, a young couple, the bartender, and the music. Otherwise, the place was empty: preserved in its own wreath of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The dim lights and lacquered tables that had been there since the thirties flickered and rested in the way they had always done. The day moved only by the sunlight that travelled across the two front windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The couple, young and beautiful and foolish looking, spoke quietly in their corner booth as though they feared their conversation would disrespect a memorial of something important and forgotten: tourists in a cemetery. The bartender was silent; he had long since left and had nothing to say. The old man was different, and yet, contributed his part to the silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And only say that you’ll be mine,&lt;br /&gt;
In no other arms entwined,&lt;br /&gt;
Down beside where the waters flow&lt;br /&gt;
On the banks of the Ohio.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The old man had been there for as long as he or anyone else could remember. He sat in the same booth by the window each afternoon, ordered the same thing, and stayed until closing. His visits to the diner became more frequent in the colder months of the year. The young couple pitied him for his old age. The bartender barely noticed him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Perhaps it was not aging desperation that kept the old man in his window booth. And perhaps, in a way, it was. But regardless of &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; it was that kept him, the old man sat there each day and each night. He drank, listened, and watched the world from his window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Surrounding the diner was old white oak and hickory forest. &lt;em&gt;It hasn’t changed since the Indians hunted these woods&lt;/em&gt;, his father used to say. Surrounding the forest were foothills. Farther out, a river flowed at their base. The old man liked it best in the summer when he could see the trees stir in a breeze he knew was warm without feeling, and the way the sunlight fell through the leaves and left its gold until the later hours of the evening. People came by more often in the summer for the view of the mountains. The old man never spoke to anyone, but he listened and felt what he heard and thought it over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I asked her if she’d marry me&lt;br /&gt;
And my wife forever be;&lt;br /&gt;
She only turned her head away&lt;br /&gt;
And had no other words to say.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;In life and its irony, the old man pitied the couple and the bartender. He pitied those who came to see the mountains in the summer as well; those who came to see the laurel and the sunsets, but left when the days were shorter and the leaves began to brown. &lt;em&gt;Certainly the summers are good here&lt;/em&gt;, he thought to himself, &lt;em&gt;but they are finer elsewhere. Winter is the truest time of these hills, but they are a strange place and one will notice it when he has stayed here for long enough&lt;/em&gt;. Even then, the old man enjoyed the mountain summers because they were motionless and thoughtlessly alive: their colors and woods and rhythm kept his mind from the things that winter brought about. Oh, the winter thoughts: there was no distinguishing the sun’s rising from its setting over the silhouettes of trees that sentineled the mountains. Everything lay as still as the particles of dust suspended in the diner’s feeble lighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And only say that you’ll be mine,&lt;br /&gt;
In no other arms entwined,&lt;br /&gt;
Down beside where the waters flow&lt;br /&gt;
On the banks of the Ohio.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt;, thought the old man, &lt;em&gt;is slower in the year’s end. Or perhaps I am the one who is slower in the year’s end and time, taking pity on me, walks by my side. I wonder&lt;/em&gt;, he thought again, &lt;em&gt;what I have left&lt;/em&gt;. The old man stopped himself from thinking in the nature of winter. The nature of winter is not one to involve oneself in. Yet, once the mind has been touched by its coldness—the coldness of the hills, particularly—it is not so easily forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What does it matter that I may not be here? It is of no importance&lt;/em&gt;. The couple paid their tab and left. The old man watched them go, but soon turned back to the window and looked outward. The sun had begun to set; day smoldering carmine to dusk. &lt;em&gt;I do not think I have ever seen the sun sink so quickly, but hell if I’ve ever seen it sink more beautifully.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I’m heading out to start my car. I’ll be back in about ten minutes and I’m going to close up shop.” The bartender left the diner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The old man, though rapt by song and dying sun, felt the door shut behind him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I took her by her golden curls,&lt;br /&gt;
I drug her down to the riverside,&lt;br /&gt;
And I there threw her into drown,&lt;br /&gt;
And I watched her as she floated down.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;If a passerby happened to stop at the diner, it might have seemed to him somewhat of an unearthly environ. The phonograph crackled a song of a bygone era, but there was no wind outside to brush against the windows and not a word uttered to warm the air. An unearthly quiet to most, however, was not but whispers of something primordial and transient to the old man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The whispers, resonating from a place that seemed to sit far beyond the line of the mountains where the river ran through denser forest, were clearer than usual to him that evening, just as the sunset was in its brilliant quietus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;How sharp, how resoundingly the whispers came at once, surrounding the old man in the perceived silence of the diner, surrounding him with memories, with moments of the present, saying to him everything and nothing at all; all things he knew and would never know; every touch, sound, taste, scent, person; each thing coming back at once like the sun’s last light; the fiercest winter storm; like the mountains and the sun and the snow and cold; all in utter silence and endless din to the old man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;It was dark now outside of the diner. The old man looked away from the window. A light flickered, the phonograph crackled, and all was as it had always been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And only say that you’ll be mine,&lt;br /&gt;
In no other arms entwined,&lt;br /&gt;
Down beside where the waters flow&lt;br /&gt;
On the banks of the Ohio.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
<author>
<name>Em Sayahi</name>
<email>limesayahi@gmail.com</email>
</author>
<title>Cinnamon</title>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2021/03/21/Cinnamon.html"/>
<pubdate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 11:25:00 +0500</pubdate>
<updated>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 11:25:00 +0500</updated>
<id>https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2021/03/21/Cinnamon.html</id>
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love cinnamon! I always forget how much I love cinnamon! Also, I just saw a big ’ol spider run past me leggies and into that toy phone on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was downright spookéd, I tell ya!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always ask myself, when presented with some cinnamon, ‘Do I like cinnamon? No, I can’t possibly like cinnamon!’ but I do, I like it a lot, and now I can’t get some more to throw in my tea because the SPIDER IS AT THE CINNAMON&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
<author>
<name>Evan Gabriel Burke</name>
<email>evanburke619@gmail.com</email>
</author>
<title>John Brown's Body</title>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2019/07/01/John Brown's Body.html"/>
<pubdate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 21:19:00 +0500</pubdate>
<updated>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 21:19:00 +0500</updated>
<id>https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2019/07/01/John Brown's Body.html</id>
<content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;It was late in the evening when we made it up the hill. The air wasn’t too hot for August and the climb wasn’t nearly as bad as it had been in July. August has a deeper shade of evening than you usually see in July: more gold, more scarlet. Greener, darker leaves in the woods, even, because of all the rain. Greener leaves, sure; but they all said it felt like the end of something. Well, that was the August of that year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“You brought it, right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Brought what?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Bread.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Why would I not bring the bread?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I was just asking.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“Of course I brought the bread, idiot.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I’d drown you if you didn’t.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I know.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;He took the loaf of soda bread and a knife from his knapsack and cut the loaf into two. Slicing it into many pieces would have been too civilized for our liking. Not long after, we had a fire going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The usual dryness of July hadn’t yet taken its toll on the valley. The landscape of Old Ohio moved itself, ancient and green and alive, over sloping hills and valleys carved long ago. The sun, in all its August glory, set fire to the West and sank below the Land of Forest and River. These hills go on forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I’ll be damned if I ever want to leave this place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;“I reckon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Al knew all the things that I knew. We were young then and felt just the same about everything. And so we ate our soda bread and had our fire. The sun fell away and the stars rose and we never noticed it until we laughed and drank and ate ourselves to the ground. The grass was cool and it all got pretty quiet and still in the summer night air. Crickets chirped, stars lingered, and we were breathless, but never tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Earlier, we had taken Old Jones’ canoe and decided to take her for a spin after we had eaten. Everything was black on the river except for the moon and the stars. Al said the heavens looked so close you could have grabbed them and kept them in your pocket if you wanted to. We switched off the paddle every so often (there was only time to borrow one before Jones came out with his shotgun) and had a great deal of fun seeing how many leaves each of us could grab from the branches we paddled under.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Both of us got tired of paddling after a while and decided to drift along see where we’d end up. We laid down with our hands in the water and sang our favorite old Civil War song, “John Brown’s Body”, the one on Al’s record. We sang it until every dog along the Ohio River joined in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;You know, everyone always says it feels like the end of something. They said it then and they say it now. I’ve never seen it like that. Back then—and Al would say the same, I think—back then, things were just the way they were. That’s how we felt about it, anyway. I guess there aren’t any of us who can explain it very well and sound like he’s in a clear state of mind. But then again, who is to begin with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;All I can tell you is that those Ohio hills are eternal. The rivers, the trees, the grasses, the dirt, the nights; they’re eternal too. We grow old, but it’s always there, one way or another. We become it surely in life, but undoubtedly in death; it’s never ending. It never really is.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
<author>
<name>Em Sayahi</name>
<email>limesayahi@gmail.com</email>
</author>
<title>My Immigrant Story</title>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2021/04/28/my-immigrant-story/index.html"/>
<pubdate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:20:36 +0000</pubdate>
<updated>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:20:36 +0000</updated>
<id>https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2021/04/28/my-immigrant-story/index.html</id>
<content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTES:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POINT: My experience as an American immigrant has shaped my ambition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining ambition
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-improvement or achievement?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desire for a life with dignity drove me to seek achievement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I didn’t have a life to be proud of, I sought self-improvement
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My name had no meaning; no connections, wealth, or history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No mark would be left by my life as it was, making the suffering pointless&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alcoholic father, schizophrenic mother, both abusive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education became a means to rise above adversity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I believe that being American means being able to succeed based on merit, because America is a land of opportunity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambition is a word that is rarely used without a connotation, implying either a consuming selfishness or an intense desire to overcome. The word is used with great promise, ‘try’ becomes ‘will’ with no guaranteed ‘how’; regardless, my father was full of ambition. A driven man, he wanted to leave a mark, a legacy, a romantic fiction in the place of an otherwise tragic story. To him, leaving something for his descendants was the only thing that could give him his personal pride, his dignity. If I were to ascribe one positive trait of mine to him, it would be my need for dignity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My father took my mother and I from Finland to the United States when I was a little under three years old, accepting a job offer he had received from a company in a city called Cincinnati. To him, it was a town comparable to the Kangasala from which he’d just left: foreign. There, and now here, our family name meant nothing. ‘Sayahi’ was a series of sounds with no history, no connections, no reputation of any sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was an alcoholic, a mean drunk and an already meaner man. Some part of him was frustratingly optimistic—everything in his life should be as he wished, and anything but was a personal attack on him. Getting his shirt stuck on a door handle was the universe inflicting upon him a pain which he’d take out on my mother and I, and later Ty, my younger brother born shortly after the move.&lt;br /&gt;
My mother was less complex, and ultimately destined for my father. She too believed everyone and everything was out to get her—paranoid schizophrenia is what the doctors called it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember very little from my life before only a handful of years ago, beyond that it was a life I wanted very desperately to forget.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
<author>
<name>Em Sayahi</name>
<email>limesayahi@gmail.com</email>
</author>
<title>Show or Tell</title>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/12/Show or Tell.html"/>
<pubdate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 21:50:00 +0400</pubdate>
<updated>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 21:50:00 +0400</updated>
<id>https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2019/09/12/Show or Tell.html</id>
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s been much debate over what constitutes art. With so many possible mediums, styles, and interpretations, art itself seems to be indefinable. Two common requirements for something to be art are: One, that the piece must be entertaining, pleasing, aesthetically beautiful, however you wish to describe it, and two, that it must express ideas and emotions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, that’s all fine and dandy, but why bother with art? You can make beautiful things, and you can say things too, but why do both? If you want to be clear and you want your ideas to be passed on, shouldn’t you just &lt;em&gt;say&lt;/em&gt; what they are? No room for interpretation, just direct and to the point. Sure, in many academic fields and other formal settings, that’s a fine option. But, when your audience consists of regular Joes and Janes, your point will just fly over their heads. They may ‘get’ it, but they won’t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; GET it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art fights biases. It uses imagery and emotion to tell a story in someone’s head. They can make judgments using their own internal logic—form an interpretation. And when someone thinks an idea is &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; idea, they’ll be less hesitant to accept it. After all, it’s their world and we’re just the ones living in it. But, what if they don’t get your point? What if someone is so different from you that your art is something completely different to them? That’s a problem many artists have faced and continue to face, and it’s been a cause for concern among many intellectuals and academics throughout time. When you write a formal essay, outlining your logic and reasoning out on a sheet of paper, sure, less people will get it, but at least those who do understand it will understand it accurately and precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say your audience does see your point. Great. You’ve done a fine job. Now you’ve got to make sure they’re convinced. Making someone hear what you’re saying is the easy part, getting them to agree with you is the thing that matters. With formal, very literal language, you could argue points and say “It’s this way because this is like this and not like that,” but then some moron will go “Well, it’s not that way because I feel it’s this way,” because they don’t &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; your point. We’re smart apes but we’re still apes, and we like to feel, not think! Art, on the other hand, can accomplish exactly that. When you tell a moving story, full of emotion—love, tragedy, the whole bunch, you appeal directly to your audience. When they can feel something, it’s more real. It isn’t just some guy’s thoughts anymore, it’s part of their reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had to sit through some boring lecture by a guy or gal that you know is fairly smart, but you just don’t care? You could agree entirely, yet you still don’t want to listen, not because you’re biased against their point of view but rather because it’s just not worth expending your brain energy to care. Thinking’s hard and not fun, so why do I have to do it if I don’t get anything out of it? That’s what your reader’s like. Your essay is that boring lecture. Art gives an audience a rush of dopamine so they stick around and get invested. I’m fairly certain almost nobody will read this essay, and I’m fairly certain most people haven’t read most essays. Because they don’t work that well. Since the dawn of time, humanity’s told stories to communicate ideas and to educate its populace, whether it be tribal tales or entire religions, “just saying” hasn’t caught on and it never will. That’s why art exists: to show, not tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
<author>
<name>Em Sayahi</name>
<email>limesayahi@gmail.com</email>
</author>
<title>Sing and Dance</title>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2021/04/23/sing-and-dance/index.html"/>
<pubdate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 13:27:00 +0000</pubdate>
<updated>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 13:27:00 +0000</updated>
<id>https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2021/04/23/sing-and-dance/index.html</id>
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I would like to sing and dance,&lt;br /&gt;
I would like to run and prance,&lt;br /&gt;
I would like to buy a dog,&lt;br /&gt;
And feed him to the wild hogs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to sing and dance,&lt;br /&gt;
I would like to run and prance,&lt;br /&gt;
I would like a box of flies,&lt;br /&gt;
Feed them to a million guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to sing and dance,&lt;br /&gt;
I would like to run and prance,&lt;br /&gt;
A loaf of bread for my poor, poor daughters&lt;br /&gt;
’Lest they become poor, poor squatters!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
<author>
<name>Evan Gabriel Burke</name>
<email>evanburke619@gmail.com</email>
</author>
<title>Tomorrow</title>
<link href="https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2020/03/24/Tomorrow.html"/>
<pubdate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 16:13:00 +0500</pubdate>
<updated>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 16:13:00 +0500</updated>
<id>https://Dirout.github.io/blog/posts/2020/03/24/Tomorrow.html</id>
<content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Some days drift by as though they have no notion of ever ending: the days that stretch on and lack the hours to count themselves with. It’s with those sorts of times one feels that whatever one is doing has always been done and will always be done and cannot possibly end, just as the day itself. Even if one moves past these times, as one tends to do, those days and everything in them sticks like briars—or clover honey, moves slow through the mind, wanders; sifts down, eventually, as the silt that forms a riverbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The man came to the railroad crossing after walking for about two hours through fields, thin honeysuckle woods, and backroads. The light beat down and the shadows of hot leaves swayed over dusty paths. The sun, resting at its zenith, caused the horizon to waver beyond the tracks. Not a train coming, not one sounding. A few clouds drifted across the midday sky; the air languished. He found a place to lie down among a grove of oaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Hours had passed, evidently, and the man had slept soundly, for the sun was set nearly to the horizon as he woke. A train whistled far off in the distance. No lights shone around the bend yet, but the long, hollow sound of a whistle was clear. If it was coming his way, he hoped it’d come slow enough to catch; if not, he’d stay for the next one or keep walking in the morning. It was too far to go back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The sun sank over the fields, now just halfway below the horizon. The train sounded again, closer this time. He stood up and looked outward: more fields, woods, railroad tracks over hills, hills over the edge of the sky; boundless sky, stained with the deep mulberry hues and gold lashes of midsummer. Farther up the tracks, there might be a railyard. Or there might be nothing for a while. &lt;em&gt;No use going back, no use going on&lt;/em&gt;. The trees hung dark now against the purple west. To think this country was once unfamiliar to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Ahead, he knew there’d be more hills and fields and hills and fields, and a few trees and such along the railway. Soon enough, a second unending landscape would rise out of the horizon and make itself known, all too well. &lt;em&gt;These trains loop west and east and back again across this country, the steel veins of the land&lt;/em&gt;. The train, whistling closer yet, was surely headed west.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;It was close enough now that he could almost see its light in the distance, almost coming around the bend, almost in view, ready to reach for. How peculiar that freight cars should be the palanquins of wanderers; scheduled, noted, regulated, moving intently from place to place like clockwork. The last light of the sun faded to blue: a soft and deep blue, all-consuming as the summer heat, over muted traces of its setting. The first few stars appeared and a breeze swelled over the tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;Suddenly, blindingly, the train hummed around the bend into sight, clanking with the force of metallic tons, roaring through the somnolent landscape on the brink of sleep just moments before. Boxcars rushed past in a blur, tearing through the quiet dusk, splintering the sounds of a lonely wooded railroad crossing with the wide-reaching blare of the whistle and the drawn-out screech of metal against metal, nothing in their wake but scattered leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;One car after another moved by in the newly fallen night. The train moved onward to its destination, farther and farther west; one car and one more following until it all disappeared from view. It seemed to have drifted by as in a dream to the man; he had seen it, but only as it rustled the trees along the railway, as unremarkable as a light wind; indeed, a dream seen from a passing glance, lightly touched, quickly forgotten. In the distance, ever so slowly, the shrill whistle fell to far-off music once again. The crossing sat as it had moments before, save for the dull fluttering of a moth between the two woodlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;The man, after standing for quite some time, began to walk westward. Surely; surely indeed he could have lifted himself onto a freightcar. How familiar is the feeling of being carried through strange lands, the wind in one’s face, the sight of the unknown laid out ahead; the vastness of it all. It was never a matter of seeking anything but one glittering nothing after another, ceaselessly, endlessly: the pith of days. Time goes running, they say. The man knew it waltzed drunkenly if you watched it long enough; anything does. Another train would sound, come around the bend, and rush by, going god knows where. &lt;em&gt;These trains loop west and east and back again…&lt;/em&gt; This was the last time, he told himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 30pt&quot;&gt;It quieted soon, and there was nothing but the murmurings of the night and the moon-white tracks before him.
</content>
</entry>
</feed>
